Oh, yes, it could be 20th century.
哦, 是了, 可能是20世纪
What's the matter with the Tardis, Doctor?
It keeps going wrong all the time.
TARDIS 出什么问题了, 博士？它总是出错
It merely needs an overhaul, Jamie,
just like any piece of machinery.
它只是需要一次大检修, Jamie, 就跟所有的机器一样
We might try and look up our old friend
Professor Travers in London.
我们试试联系我们在伦敦的老朋友 Travers 教授
- He might be able to help us, hmm?
- Yeah. Aye.
- 他也许能帮助我们, 嗯？  - 嗯, 是的
Always supposing he's not a baby or a schoolboy!
Now come along!
一直觉得他不是一个婴儿或者学童．快过来吧
Let's just collect this circuit
我们收集一下电路
There.
那里
Yes. It's all right.
It's just a fault in the visual stabiliser circuit.
是的, 这没问题．只是视觉稳定器电路有点故障
It's, uh... We'd better take that, too.
这是...我们最好把那个也带上
- Er... Can you give us a lift to London?
- Yes, I suppose so.
- 呃, 你能捎我们去伦敦吗？  - 行, 我觉得可以
DOCTOR: In you get.
你们进去
Thank you. Thank you very much.
谢谢你, 非常感谢
- DOCTOR: Here we are.  - Right
- 我们到啦  - 对了
Well, that's odd! It says ''Watkins''./?
诶, 很奇怪, 上面写的 "Watkins"
(JAMIE) Must have the wrong house.
肯定搞错房子了
Well, the telephone directory
definitely said number 1 8.
啊, 电话号码簿上绝对写的是 18 号啊
We'll ask.
我们问问
(DOORBELL RINGING INCESSANTLY)
If you don't mind, I'm trying to work!
不介意的话, 我还要工作呢！
Oh. I'm sorry, miss, but we wondered
whether you could help us.
噢, 抱歉, 小姐．但我们想问问你能否帮助我们
We wondered if...
我们想知道...
Oh, look, now the stupid thing's gone and jammed!
噢, 看, 这个蠢东西又卡住了
Oh, dear, perhaps I could help you.
噢, 亲爱的, 也许我可以帮你
Well, do you know anything about cameras?
哦, 你还懂一点相机？
Yes, a little. I see...
是的, 一点点．我知道了...
Now I had it on automatic shutter.
现在我调到了自动快门模式
Taking photos of yourself?
在自拍呢？
Yes, then you interrupted me
and the stupid thing jammed!
是的, 然后你们打断了我, 这个破玩意儿就卡住了
Have you come to see my uncle?
He's not here.
你们是来找我叔叔的吧？他现在不在这里
But who are you?
Friends of his? Fellow nuts?
但你们是谁？他的朋友？也是技术迷?
Please let me answer one question at a time.
且让我一个个地回答
Hey, you be careful with that thing.
It cost me a fortune.
嘿, 你小心弄这个东西, 它花了我不少钱
It's all right. It's a very simple mechanism.
没事的, 非常简单的机制
- Who is your uncle?  - Professor Watkins.
- 你叔叔是谁？  - Watkins 教授
Oh.
哦
Then Professor Travers doesn't live here?
那 Travers 教授不住在这里？
Well, he did. He left about a month ago.
哦, 以前是．他大概一个月前离开了
Gone to America for a year with his daughter.
跟他女儿一起去非洲待一年
Oh, that's just great!
噢, 那太棒了！
My uncle worked at the Cavendish lab.
我叔叔在 Cavendish 实验室工作
He wanted to do some work so Professor Travers said
他想做点工作, 于是 Travers 教授说
he could use his daughter's lab here.
他可以用他女儿的这个实验室
And I moved in because I got kicked
out of my studio last week.
而我搬进来是因为我上周被踢出我的工作室了
What field of science is your uncle in?
你叔叔研究的是哪个领域？
Oh, I don't know,
he's in applied physics or something.
哦, 我不知道．他是搞应用物理什么的吧
Always messing around with computers
and things. Complete nut.
总是在摆弄电脑这些．完全的疯子
Well, that is fortunate.
Perhaps he might be able to help us.
哦, 那很幸运啊, 也许他可以帮助我们
- Is he at home?  - No.
- 他在家吗？  - 不在
- Well, where is he?
- Well, how do I know? I'm not his keeper.
- 那, 他在哪儿？  - 哦, 我怎么知道？我不是他的管家
- Hey, have you fixed it?
- Oh, yes, that's all right.
- 嘿, 你修好了吗？  - 哦, 是的, 没事了
- That's really great, thanks!  - Miss...
- 真是太好了, 谢谢！  - 小姐...
Hey!
嘿！
That's a jolly outfit.
Would you mind posing for me?
这真是件漂亮的衣服．你介意摆个姿势给我吗？
- What?  - Look. Just stand there.
- 什么？  - 喏, 就站那里
- Miss!  - Isobel.
- 小姐！  - 我叫 Isobel
Yeah, okay. Now just stand here.
Now get... Head over the shoulder.
对, 好．就站在那里．现在...把头朝肩膀过去一点
Have you any idea
when your uncle is going to be back?
知道你叔叔什么时候回来吗？
No, he left about a week ago.
I haven't seen him since.
不, 他大概一周前走的, 从那之后我就没见过他
A week?
一周？
Yeah, he was prattling on about some
new invention, or something or other,
是, 他一直在叨叨什么新发明, 不知道是什么东西
and having the chance to develop it.
Now... Not you.
说有机会来研究它了．现在...不是你
- Oh.  - ISOBEL: Okay. Now.
- 噢  - 好, 现在
Can't you get in touch with him?
你能联系上他吗？
No, I tried.
不能, 我试过
I wanted to borrow a couple of quid
off him in a hurry,
我想找他借几镑救救急
but, well, they said
he wasn't available for phone calls.
但是, 他们说他没法接电话
They! Now... Now who is ''they''?
他们！说说..."他们"是谁？
Just get that, will you? I don't know.
拿着这个, 好吗？我不知道
International Electric, something or other.
好像是叫＂国际电子＂, 好像是吧
International Electromatics?
国际电气自动化公司？
Yes, probably.
是, 像是
You mean your uncle has gone to
work for these people?
你是说你叔叔去为这些人工作了？
- Mmm-hmm.
- Well, surely we can get in touch with him.
- 嗯哼  - 那, 我们当然可以联系上他了
Well, you can try telephoning,
but I doubt if you'll get any joy.
是, 你可以试着打打电话, 但我怀疑你不会得到好结果
Oh, phone's in the hall and
the number's scribbled on the wall.
哦, 电话就在大厅里, 号码写在墙上呢
Thank you.
谢谢你
Hey. Don't go.
嘿, 不要走
I don't often get the chance of
photographing a real model.
我并不是总有机会能给一个真正的模特拍照片
Oh, all right.
噢, 好吧
Come on. Let's get you fixed up with some gear!
快来, 我们来给你拍几张好看的(?)
WOMAN: International Electromatic Company.
State your business.
国际电气自动化公司．请陈述你的目的
I would like, please,
to speak with Professor Watkins.
我想要, 请帮忙, 与 Watkins 教授通话
One moment.
等一下
- Party not available.
- Oh, yes. You see, but this is very important.
- 当事人不在  - 噢, 这样．你看, 这事非常重要
Party not available.
当事人不在
- Yes, but I must speak with him.
- Party not available.
- 是的, 但我必须同他通话  - 当事人不在
- But this is an automatic answering device!
- 当事人不在  - 这是一台自动应答设备！
Ah, shut up, you stupid machine!
啊, 闭嘴, 你个愚蠢的机器！
- So, now what?
- There's only one thing for it!
- 那, 现在怎办？  - 就只有一件事可做了！
We'll have to go there ourselves.
我们只能自己去那里
Okay, that's fabulous, just keep it like that.
好, 那样很漂亮, 就这样保持住
Great. Any luck?
很好．运气如何？
No, it was a stupid simple-minded
computer answering service.
不怎样, 只有一个愚蠢而死脑筋的电脑应答服务
Well, what do we do now?
那, 我们现在怎么做？
Well, Jamie and I are going to this place.
Come on, Zoe.
Jamie 和我打算去那个地方．来吧, Zoe
Oh, no, thanks. I think I'll stay here.
It's great fun.
哦, 不, 谢谢．我想我还是待在这里, 这很有意思
You look like a chicken with all those feathers on!
你穿上那些衣服就像一只小鸡！
Well, come on, Jamie. Oh, the address?
好, 来吧, Jamie．哦, 地址有吗？
- Oh, that's scribbled on the wall, too.
- DOCTOR: Oh, thank you.
- 哦, 也在墙上写着呢  - 哦, 谢谢你
Do you not write anything down on paper at all?
你是什么都不写在纸上吗？
Well, I'd only lose it if I did.
要是我写在纸上的话, 只会把它弄丢
Writing on a wall is much safer.
You can't lose a wall, can you?
写在墙上安全多了．你不可能弄丢一堵墙, 是吧？
No.
不能
HQ are checking now. Where are they?
总部在检查了, 他们在哪儿？
Gone round the back, down the side alley.
从后面绕过去了, 在旁边那个小巷里
It's a dead end, isn't it?
So they've got to come out this way!
那是条死路, 对吧．所以他们还是会从这条路出来！
If they come out.
那得假设他们会出来
Come and sit down, gentlemen.
过来坐下, 先生们
DOCTOR: Thank you.
谢谢你
- You can go, Packer.  - Yes, sir.
- 你可以走了, Packer  - 好的, 先生
I must apologise for Packer's
crude devotion to duty.
Packer 只知道忠于职守, 我必须为他的粗鲁道歉
But your method of entry into my building
was rather...unconventional, wasn't it?
但你们进入我这大楼的方式也是相当地...打破传统了, 是不？
- Aye, well, there was no need for all that...
- Jamie!
- 是, 嗯, 没有必要费那个劲...  - Jamie！
...gas and stuff.
...这些虚假的客套
I think perhaps it is we
who should be apologising to you, Mr...
我觉得应该是我们向你道歉, 先生...
Vaughn. Tobias Vaughn.
Vaughn. 我叫 Tobias Vaughn.
I'm the Managing Director
of International Electromatics.
我是国际电气自动化公司的执行董事
Your business must be very pressing
to force you to such extremes.
你们的事情肯定非常紧迫, 才迫使你们采取了如此极端的手段
Yes, it is.
是的, 的确
- Concerning Professor Watkins?
- How did you know?
- 与 Watkins 教授有关吗？  - 你怎么知道？
My computer. It reported directly to me.
我的电脑．它直接向我报告了
Oh, I see.
噢, 我明白了
You've gone to a lot of trouble for nothing, you know.
你们费尽周折却是徒劳, 知道吧
The Professor's working on an experiment
and refuses to see anyone.
教授正忙于一项实验, 拒绝见任何人
Ah, well. We only want to talk to him, you see.
啊, 其实, 我们只是想同他说几句话, 你看
Perhaps I can help.
也许我能帮上忙
No, I don't think so, thank you very much.
不, 我不觉得, 非常感谢
Oh, come on, Doctor,
it's only a couple of electronic circuits.
噢, 快点, 博士．只是一些电子线路
(GRUNTING)
Circuits? Electronic circuits?
电路？电子线路？
My technicians are the best in the world.
我的技术人员是这个世界最好的
I'm sure they'd be able to assist you.
我确定他们可以帮到你
- Show me the circuits.  - Well, I...
- 把电路给我看看  - 这个, 我...
Please, I'd like to help.
拜托, 我想帮忙
As you say, rather complex.
如你所说, 相当复杂
- However, I'm sure we'll be able to help you.
- Yes. You see...
- 然而, 我确定我们能帮助你  - 是的, 你看...
I'll have them sent to my workshops immediately.
我会安排人马上送到我的工作间
- Oh, how very kind.  - Not at all.
- 噢, 太给力了  - 不用
Professor Watkins is a valued colleague.
Any friend of his is... Oh.
Watkins 教授是一位重要的同事．他的任何朋友都是...噢
- Have you got one of these, young man?
- No, what is it?
- 这个东西你有吗, 年轻人  - 没有, 是什么？
Surely you've seen them about.
They're disposable transistor radios.
你肯定见过它们．它们是便携性晶体管收音机
One of our latest products. Most popular.
我们最新的一项产品, 非常畅销
We've sold 10 million in this country alone. Here.
我们仅仅在这个国家就买了一千万个．给你
Compensation for the treatment
you received from the worthy Packer.
作为对你的补偿, 考虑到 Packer 对你的招待不周
Thank you. How does it work?
谢谢你, 它是怎么打开的？
(UPBEAT INSTRUMENTAL MUSIC PLAYING)
Yes, that's how you turn it off, Jamie.
是的, 这样你就可以关掉它了, Jamie
Now, if you'll excuse me,
I'm afraid I have an urgent appointment.
现在, 如果你们没意见, 恐怕我还有一个紧急会议
Yes, of course. Come along, Jamie.
好, 当然了．来吧, Jamie
Packer will meet you
and show you the way out, Mr...
Packer 会过来, 带你们出去, 这位...
- Doctor. Goodbye.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
- 博士．再见  - 再见, 博士
Goodbye, Mr Vaughn, and thank you for the radio.
再见, Vaughn 先生．谢谢你的收音机
Not at all.
不用谢
- Packer?  - Yes, Mr Vaughn?
- Packer?  - 什么事, Vaughn 先生？
Show our visitors off the premises, will you?
带我们的客人离开, 好吗？
Very good, sir.
很好, 先生
PACKER: The next time,
read the notice on the door.
下一次,读一下门上的警告
JAMIE: Oh, don't tell me you can read as well.
What else do you do?
哦, 别告诉我你也识字．你还会干什么？
Jamie!
Jamie!﻿
That fellow's not what he seems.
那个家伙并不是他看起来那样
That big idiot? Oh, don't worry.
I'll soon sort...
那个傻大个？不用担心．我很快就能...
No, no, no. I mean Vaughn.
不, 不, 不．我是说 Vaughn
Oh, and he's got a forked tail and wee horns.
噢, 他有一条分叉的尾巴, 头上还有角
Oh, I'm not joking, Jamie.
哦, 我不是在开玩笑, Jamie
Underneath all that charm,
there was something odd.
外表上很有魅力, 但底下总觉得有点古怪
Sinister. Almost inhuman.
很邪恶．感觉不像人类